I own the team tonight Desiree Bianca
callate will be inducted by Councilman
Anthony Branca telling you the accept
advice white count we're 12 councilman
Anthony bracket le he's been serving
since 2005 and will ever forever be
linked the judge cannot have burger but
they did what they championed during the
national foreclosure crisis chandi the
fight for neighborhoods of people he is
the chairman of the Cuyahoga County
underutilization corporation that's
basically County campaign and what they
do is in turn pad properties of the good
that raised interests structures they
replace them with new development for
community charters he is the grandson of
Polish Italian immigrants and has been a
lifelong resident of Slavic the
hinterland for nonsense Francisco Lindor
had a two-run homer
[Applause]
and that would be very clear we're not
just here to lead us to number of great
recipes we're here for our children
we're different people that celebrates
our future I'm pretty good mild ascetic
my son thinks the world of Joe simple
and a global cleaning I'm pretty
compensate that it's not just an
all-around under way and it made exam is
for children this is our future this is
what we to us so I mean I told the folks
with a housing program if you look at
them I'll start crying but it's really
important what's going on on a world
that's really important for us to
embrace her future so when I went out of
the novel's I can't help but look at you
know the great things that would happen
in our communities I was told that we
had two minutes to introduce our
inductee but Mr Feliciano you took 15
and then the thank you very much for the
student arrangements because you kept
chief up here at the council Wayne back
so we understand the separation of both
those parties but I'm a council
president County Councilman Santana for
coming out from Taiwan this is pretty
amazing and the politician at the
capital paid nothing he has anything to
do with that Republican Party but let's
talk about you would say mother Mary
Marvel she started on the east side she
was a smuggler good reporter she decided
she was written in Slavic village so we
know where she started from and Joe
Kelly and his thank you very much for
your presence here today is very
important so I believe this it's great
to be here tonight and our enjoy Bianca
and certainly for Karen and Kirsten I
can't
to recognize for this kind of
nationality movements and so I did
prepare a speech and usually speak ought
to talk place not break time when I was
doing this so this reply honor that
standard the data we chose radiometer
and to the Cleveland International Hall
of Fame but I also stand here with a
profound sense of sadness still there
any of this shock as we all do is untie
and oppression we're integrated man
we're gonna celebrate these
accomplishments and give me this game
deserves as an inductee the Great Hall
the thing one thing Dan and Debbie and
all the members for all of what they do
it was a wonderful event explained Rick
as a model citizen one supports all the
work that he did to boost our city
preserve our heritage in stimulus growth
and development as a grassroots
community activist America City Council
of doom and neighborhood residents and
fought for services and resources to
keep our communities five Americans safe
and rain I showed a lot of compassion
and militiamen are Polish marriage is
compromise
right down the middle of Italian
immigrants and
debate if he knew when we would argue
about war poverty and every can share
those stories with us and he said work
boundaries I was in a country in Poland
was a word about country mountains not a
lot more comedies but Britain's always
about public service generic translator
Robert filmmaker now Scott Lewis
described him as a humble a student of
history courageous and pathetic filled
with a sometimes
corny sense of humor and directed by a
belief that might be more fair rate was
truly a man
has a little passion get the passion for
the city of Cleveland which he lived his
life and he had compassion for those
less fortunate struggling to make a
living for themselves their families as
both the prices and a public official
ray serving in an impact growing up on
clippings near West Side he showed early
signs of leadership and he became the
class president of West High School so
American sense key and we work very
closely with Ray Ray start at a very
young age that's the one bring it up in
1973 ray became a founder of the first
executive director of nutritional
recommendation a liver a year later he
married his high school sweetheart Eric
Wilson and in 1985 at age 34 he became a
city councilman representative West Side
neighborhoods
I had a previous article eponymous trip
anybody from The Plain Dealer speery but
when he was on leather
he fought about trees that were felled
in his neighborhood from storm and he
won the whole street can be put back up
and he petitioned then councilman zone
not Maxim with his dad difficult trees
we planted in our neighborhood how's my
man zone apologize it could not make it
today but he does recognize the fact
that he petitions dead to say pickles
3-foot back up and it's a London he got
that time
as a member of council Canadian economic
government many great champion in web
development and innovative ways to
preserve our city's historic buildings
and to be cleared if it wasn't for raid
the grand capital theater and importance
where arcade Wesley for Detroit would
not be stands in an ethical it was
condemned that ready for the wrecking
ball as a historic interpreter stories
and connect roms of nearly every street
instruction assited Cleveland great
could not bear the thought of the
wrecking ball full swing against that
his broker arcade and I tell the story
that may be tough now because it's not
with us in trouble but indeed properties
being over a waterfall
they keep the white apartment who say
they've been shutting the water off in
that beautiful building they get those
credits residents under there and he was
one of those kind of folks who really
stood up for the small folks after
serving 10 years the City Council rated
in Cleveland's municipal housing court
Jones together a professional and
dedicated to keep pressure than a navy
landlord since 1996 he served Cletus
housing court judge Reagan our judge of
2000 2007 and 2013 while serving as
judge he sometimes said to someone are
slipping Lipton house arrest in their
home dilapidated properties and he held
a big international banks and mortgage
companies in contempt of court as deputy
I was dropping hearings
as an Espada Kirk generates bureaucracy
develop small cameras and turn an
addiction bankers involving suffering
mortgage schemes that a nineteen
nineties where the gravity nor
neighborhoods general characters as a
member to the City Council helped to
create the housing court said that the
role was still made for judge Bianca so
between all brokers he has his housing
clinics mentor clinic retro grant rent
reconnaissance he created a number of
programs that today still stand as a
model for our forget programs I do want
to recommend this judge with Larry and
as many policy court folks who are here
tonight please aim to give recommend for
the great work with judges and all those
on the court for falling under judge
[Music]
this curve is honesty this vision
infected positive change in our
community and we're all grateful to
heaven and have to been inspired by
minute he must wrote nothing that has
done nothing that they have done or
could do to serve my community is more
important or more fulfilling than being
housing court judge today the raid still
holds a distinction of being that this
longest-serving housing court judge and
so I know I left my phone up there but
there was my last message before ray
passed away about 1866 in Colorado where
he called me and said you have to do
something about this property you could
be responsible the city has his hand up
and after he passed away that was my one
plan long-standing goal I didn't get the
drag attractor to bulldoze that property
but I understood how important was to
Ray in our communities and how was
important that we stood up for our
neighborhoods so as tough as he was if a
homeowner Kingdom of Heaven all
financial means to correct for code
violations rates at the mercy and
independent and work to find ways to fix
up the house and helped all pulmonary
different answers big where it's truly a
minute compassion is what was passion
yet the passion for the city of
Cleveland which would live his entire
life and a compassion for those of us
sports and expert more than making
living for themselves in their families
for a person calling for something else
he was downright national initiative
that incredible mind pristinely tell you
everything about every single property
in our neighborhoods and the city as
well
great was had a successful and historic
preservationist which i had no very
involved as the medics protocol in our
community he was constantly talking
about saying how do we
these properties particle radioactivity
so well and the city so well was it a
lot the streets and then any given day
rate walk the number of miles off my way
preparing and side by side they would
walk in neighborhoods ray didn t serve
the community obviously little fanfare
he has many Ward's on the tour old
Cleveland work ethic that both our city
I have a couple of works that gives
received over time before anal warts
which I'm proud to wear today as a night
he was proud of his work this family in
his fullest heritage all the knowledge
countless wrote about great binocular
these are the oldest Islander he's
hoping you almost aspire to do with that
beautiful tomorrow
I humbly submit to you the induction
event in Tanaka put a clip Menendez from
hall of fame of itinerant and Kristen
Pianka to the stage
[Applause]
[Music]
we are so sorry that my dad could not be
here to accept this award we miss his
commitment to and he reminds his vast
knowledge of our city and most of all
his compassion for people
[Applause]
[Music]